# William Huang

## **Software Development Engineer**

Beltsville, MD | huang.william6688@gmail.com | 240-636-2339 | LinkedIn | GitHub

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a student at the University of Maryland, College Park majoring in Computer Science and minoring in Statistics. I worked as an Amazon Web Services (AWS) software development engineer (SDE) intern last summer. I look forward to continuing to gain experience with new development tools to one day lead diverse teams on innovative solutions as a Tech Lead.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Maryland, College Park

Aug 2021 - Present

- Computer Science Major and Statistics Minor
- Business, Society, and the Economy (BSE) Scholars Program

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Amazon Web Services (AWS), Incoming SDE Intern

May 2023 – Aug 2023

• Will contribute to the largest global cloud platform

United States Geological Survey (USGS), Contractor, Software Engineer

Jul 2020 – Jan 2022

- Created an image-matching database program with Python's OpenCV package
- Used deep learning with hundreds of data points to crop out the background of images
- Utilized machine learning algorithms and tools to process images over 10x more accurately
- Guided new recruits on company guidelines and projects through emails and GitHub

CloakClub App, Founder, Software Development Engineer, UX/UI Designer Feb 2019 – Jun 2021

- Utilized Flutter programming development language for a mobile app that was accessible on both Apple and Andriod devices
- Designed and integrated a clean, easily, understood user interface with harmonious widget placement and a beautiful color scheme
- Structured CloakClub database with Firebase and stored information with efficient data structures and algorithms
- Tested code and launched refined product to the Apple App Store and Google Play Store

#### **SKILLS**

- Software: Java, C, C++, C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flutter, Python, Dart, R, Swift, SQL, SQLite, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Firebase, BeautifulSoup, Rust, Ocaml, Ruby, Dafny, Haskell
- Languages: English, Chinese

#### **ACTIVITIES**

## Bitcamp 2023, Software Engineer

Apr 2023 - Apr 2023

- Competed against 400 teams to win the Best Gamification Hack award
- Utilized Swift, Python, Flask, and OpenAI's DALL-E 2 API to create an iOS app that gamifies machine learning processes

#### Northrop Grumman Innovation Factory Hackathon, Group Leader

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

- Built a web scrapper that scrapped Amazon reviews using Python's BeautifulSoup
- Used OpenAI's Da-Vinci natural language processing model API to determine the authenticity of a review
- Developed an intuitive user interface using Flask and JavaScript and directed a live demo